Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Non-Proprietary Research Reports, 1980-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Non-Proprietary Research Reports 1980-1999
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office.
6.8 linear feet Extent: 250 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00674
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Non-Proprietary Research Reports were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1999.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) was founded in New York, N.Y., in 1864, and is one of the world's largest advertising agencies.
Collection Overview
Collection created by the JWT Chicago Office Information Center as a reference and research tool for business use. The term non-proprietary is JWT's term for research prepared or collected by the company but not on behalf of specific clients. The collection includes market and consumer research reports arranged alphabetically by subject. A small number of items represent JWT research done, but most were created by market research firms (e.g., Yankelovich, Elmo Roper and Associates), cable TV stations (e.g., MTV Networks), or magazines (e.g., Seventeen, Good Housekeeping), and others. Topics include consumer demographic analyses for the United States, especially of food and beverage products and restaurant services. Marketing to women is a major subject; there is also information on marketing to men, baby boomers, teens, and children. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History. (02-256)
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Research; Marketing research -- United States; Consumer behavior; Women consumers -- United States; Women -- United States -- Attitudes; Male consumers -- United States; Men -- United States -- Attitudes; Teenage consumers -- United States; Consumers; Consumers -- Attitudes; Motivation research (Marketing); Food -- Marketing; Food industry and trade -- United States; Child consumers; Advertising and children; Children -- Attitudes; Baby boom generation -- United States -- Attitudes; Baby boom generation -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0256
  - Baby Market
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Baby Food - 1984 (Box 1)
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Baby Food - 1988 (Box 1)
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Nursing Accessories and Breastfeeding trends- 1988 (Box 1)
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Skin Care - 1984 (Box 1)
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Furniture and Nursery Accessories - 1988 (Box 1)
    - Baby Products Tracking Study - Children's Clothing- 1988 (Box 1)
  - Baby Boomers
    - The Boomer Generation as Consumers ( 1986) (Box 1)
    - Baby Boomers in Mid-Passage (Box 1)
    - The Experts Guide to the Baby Boomers ( 1985) (Box 1)
  - Children
    - Communicating with Children ( 1981) (Box 1)
    - Nickelodeon...Youth Monitor ( 1990) (Box 1)
    - The American Chicle Youth Poll ( 1987) (Box 1)
    - Chasing After the Kids ( 1994) (Box 1)
    - How to make successful advertising to Children (London - 1993) (Box 1)
    - Articles on Kids, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Kids Magnet (on children's magazine readership ca. 1994) (Box 1)
  - College Students
    - MTV College Scan - They Don't Just Watch It, They Live It. 1989 (Box 1)
    - Today's College Students - misc. articles, reports (Box 1)
  - Consumers
    - Family Circle Consumer Panel, Winter 1994 (Box 1)
    - Wall Street Journal Series - American Way of Buying 1989 + (Box 2)
    - Misc. Reports (nuclear family, influential people, trends...) (Box 2)
    - The Changing American Family, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Male Food Shopper
    - The Male Food Shopper (Campbell Soup and People Magazine - 1985 (Box 2)
  - Men
    - American Male Opinion Index - GQ ( 1990s) (Box 2)
  - Middle Aged Markets
    - Exploding the Myth of the Middle-Aged Market (CBS) 1993 (Box 2)
  - Money
    - Various reports and articles ( 1990s) (Box 2)
  - Seniors + (Mature, 49 +)
    - Midlife and Beyond (Box 3)
    - The Mature Americans (Box 3)
    - Misc. (OSRIP Note - 8/1995 and A Portrait of Older Minorities ca. 1980) (Box 3)
    - Insights into the Over 50 Market (Box 3)
    - The Shifting American Marketplace (Boomers and Aging) - CBS/Time 1989 (Box 3)
  - Teens
    - Misc. ( 1990s) (Box 3)
    - Seventeen - My Generation ( 1986) (Box 3)
    - Teens (Food, Nutrition, Etc. - 1980s - 1990s) (Box 3)
    - America's Youth - 1977 - 1988 (Box 3)
    - TRU - 1985 - Research from Seventeen ( 1985-1991) (Box 3)
    - TRU Study - No. 6 - The Teenage Market - 1985 (Box 3)
    - Seventeen Research - 1995, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Women
    - Today's Mom - Role of Motherhood Study - 1998 (Box 4)
    - Misc. Reports, early 1990s (Box 4)
    - Marketing to Women (Box 4)
    - Working Women - A Social Value Perspective - 1985 (Box 4)
    - Today's American Woman - How the public sees her- 1980 (Box 4)
  - Women - Mademoiselle Magazine Studies
    - Misc. Reports - 1990s (Box 4)
  - Women - Self Magazine
    - The New Diversity: A Landmark Study of American Women Vol. 1-5 (Box 4)
  - Women - Cosmopolitan Studies
    - Cosmopolitan - Report on the Changing Life Course of American Women - Summary of reports, and Vol. 1 - 3 - 1986 (Box 5)
  - Women - Exercise
    - The Health and Fitness Survey, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Women and Food - Condé Nast
    - Women and Food II: A Study for Food Marketers in the Nineties ( ca. 1988) (Box 5)
  - Automotive Industry
    - Aftermarket Fact Books - 1990s (Box 5)
    - 1996 Dohring National Automotive Consumer Study (Box 5)
    - How Men Buy their Cars and Trucks - 1995 (Box 5)
    - The Market for New Cars IV ( 1990) (Box 5)
  - ADA (American Dietetic Association)
    - Surveys - 1991, 1993, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Beverages
    - Alcohol - Use and Abuse - 1985 (Box 6)
    - Beverage Preferences - NRA - 1989 (Box 6)
    - Coffee Drinking Study - late 1980s (Box 6)
    - Annual Statistical Review of Distilled Spirits Industry 1983/1984 (Box 6)
  - Better Homes and Gardens
    - Consumer Food Panel (Box 6)
    - Housecleaning (Box 6)
    - Physical Fitness (Box 6)
  - Confectionery
    - Confectionery Industry Consumer Attitude Survey, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Diet, Nutrition and Cancer (Box 6)
  - Diet, Nutrition and Cancer: A Critique 1982 (Box 6)
  - Dinner
    - Dinnertime USA (Better Homes and Gardens Report, 1989) (Box 6)
  - Ethnic
    - Blackbook - International Reference Guide - 1985 (Box 6)
    - Spanish USA, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Family Circle - Nutrition and The Family ( c. 1993) (Box 6)
  - Food Marketing Institute (FMI)/Better Homes and Gardens Studies
    - A Study of Food Patterns and Meal Consumption - 1988 (Box 6)
  - FMI Trends Studies 1985-1997 (Box 6)
  - FMI Trends Studies 1985-1997 (cont.) (Box 7)
  - FMI - Misc. Studies - 1990s (Box 7)
  - Gallup Report on Eating Out ( 1986, 1987) (Box 7)
  - Good Housekeeping Food Studies ( 1987 - 1990) (Box 7)
  - Good Housekeeping Food Studies ( 1987 - 1990) (cont.) (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping (GH) - Home Care Studies 1987 - 1990 (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping - Kitchen 1989-1992 (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping - Consumer Studies 1992, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping - Women/Environment 1990 (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping - Changing Mood of America - Quarterly Newsletters 1991 (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping - Beyond Demographics 1994 (Box 8)
  - Conference Board and US Census Bureau - How We Live - Then and Now 1986 (Box 8)
  - McCall's Study - 1994 (Box 8)
  - Wisconsin
    - Dairy Facts - 1984-1986 (Box 8)
    - Agricultural Stats - 1994 (Box 8)
  - NPD Reports
    - Eating Trend Report - 1986 (Box 8)
    - Eating Trend Report - 1987, 1990, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Meat Outlook
    - The Meat Outlook - 1990 (Box 9)
  - Parents Magazine
    - Food Survey - 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Parade Magazine
    - Food Studies c. 1987 - 1995 (Box 9)
  - Pillsbury and Ameripoll
    - What's Cooking c. 1986 (Box 9)
    - Grocery Store Habits - 1989 (Box 9)
  - Prevention
    - 1985-1993 Index of Health Issues Surveys (Box 9)
    - Nutrition as a Lifestyle (American Women) - c. 1987 (Box 9)
    - Prevention Update: Fiber, Cholesterol, Omega-3, Calcium, Diet Nutrition, Cancer - 1987 (Box 9)
    - Various Reports, late 1980s - early 1990s. (Box 9)
  - Ragu
    - Food Trends in America, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Research Alert
    - Report, December 1989 (Box 10)
  - Restaurants
    - Investment Analysis Reports - 1990s (Box 10)
  - Shopping À La Cart (FMI)
    - The Changing Environment of the Take-Out Food Market - 1987 (Box 10)
  - Home Delivery/Take-Out
    - Report: Home Delivery and Take-Out Foodservice Systems, c. 1990. (Box 10)
  - Dinner Decision Making
    - National Restaurant Association Report - 1995 (Box 10)
  - The New Food Market
    - Rolling Stone Report, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Food - Eating Habits of Mature
    - The Eating Habits of Mature Americans, Roper Report, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Self - Nutrition
    - Trends in Nutrition IV - 1986 (Box 10)
  - Sunset
    - Western Market Almanac, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - What the Customer Wants
    - What the Customer Wants in the 1990s (Wall Street Journal/Roper) - 1990 (Box 10)
  - Food Shopping, Misc.
    - Food Shopping in One-Person Households (N.A.B.) - 1983 (Box 10)
    - Supermarket Shoppers in a period of Economic Uncertainty, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Better Homes and Garden - Vacation Travel
    - 1995 Survey (Box 10)
  - Cruises
    - 1989, 1990 Reports (Box 10)
  - Marketing Science Institute (MSI)
    - Reports on Marketing Topics, 1997-1999 - scattered. (Box 11)
    - Reports on Marketing Topics, 1997-1999 - scattered. (cont.) (Box 12)